JORGE MORENO. @alterebro

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER & UI DESIGNER

> Personal Website : www.moro.es

> Github Profile : github.com/alterebro

> LinkedIn Profile : linkedin.com/in/alterebro

> Contact e-mail : alterebro@gmail.com

> Skype ID : alterebro

SUMMARY

Hi! This is Jorge, I'm User Interface Developer from Zaragoza, Spain. With more than 10 years of professional experience developing websites and web applications my major focus and specialise is in Front End Web Development using web standard technologies (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript) but my skillset includes an extensive knowledge in Web Design & UI / UX Design and a wide experience of server side programming using PHP and MySQL.

The knowledge of multiple fields and the creative mindset I forged with my Arts background (Degree in Design & Illustration) allows me to work on a project with a unique perspective and the full scope in mind.

If you want to have further information about me or the work I do, visit my personal website www.moro.es or feel free to send me an e-mail to alterebro@gmail.com.

CORE SKILLS

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT

- > HTML5 Semantic markup, Cross Browser and following best practice W3C accessibility standards and guidelines (WCAG 2).
- CSS3, CSS Pre processors (LESS and SCSS/Sass) and CSS Frameworks (Bootstrap, Skeleton, Foundation).
- > JavaScript native client side programming (aka Vanilla JS), AJAX, libraries like jQuery, Zepto.js, P5.js, Processing.js.. and MVVM Frameworks such as Vue.js or AngularJS.
- > Responsive Design (RWD) and cross device compatible development.
- > Front End automation with Task runners / Build systems : Grunt, Gulp, Webpack.
- > Source code Version control workflow with Git / GitHub.

SERVER SIDE WEB DEVELOPMENT

- > PHP programming and database integration (MySQL, SQLite) under LAMP, WAMP and MAMP environments.
- > CMS Content Management Systems customization and theming (WordPress, ExpressionEngine, WolfCMS..)
- > PHP Libraries (GD2, iMagick, Idiorm ...), Frameworks (Slim), Templating (Twig, Mustache...) and XML & JSON RESTful Web Services integration
- > Web Scraping and Data Mining + Extraction.

UX/UI WEB DESIGN

- > Website and Web Applications User Interface (UI) Layout Design and User Experience (UX).
- > Wireframing, Prototyping and Mockup creation both static and interactive via 'Design in browser'
- > Design software : Adobe PhotoShop, Illustrator, Inkscape.

EXTRA / MISC

- > Cross Platform Mobile Application development with PhoneGap and Apache Cordova.
- > Creative programming using the Processing Language.
- > Open Source Contributor.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance UI Designer & Front End Web Developer. (Remote based)

02/2015 - Present

Website and Web Applications Design and Development. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL.

> Creative Technologist at 72andSunny. (Los Angeles, CA, US)

09/2014 - 12/2014

Concept Design and Creative Coding: Arduino, Processing, P5.js, PHP

> UI Developer at Adidas Group

08/2013 - 07/2014

Mobile Apps UI Design & Hybrid Applications Responsive FrontEnd Development: HTML5, LESS, CSS3, JavaScript (jQuery + Zepto).

> Web Developer at William Hill PLC (Gibraltar, UK)

01/2013 - 08/2013

PHP, HTML, CSS & JavaScript. FrontEnd + BackEnd Development & ExpressionEngine CMS Customization.

> Web Developer at Malmor Diseño SL

12/2009 - 06/2012

FrontEnd Development: HTML, CSS & JavaScript + Backend Development: PHP & MySQL.

> Web App Designer and Front End Developer at Strands Labs, Inc (Barcelona, Madrid, ES. Boise, ID, US)

02/2008 - 07/2009

Front End Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, mooTools, ExtJS. Web App Design for desktop and mobile devices (iPhone, Nokia Symbian and Blackberry)

> Web Designer and Front End Developer at The Design Factory Ltd (London, UK) 03/2004 - 01/2008

Website user interface design, front end development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ActionScript. Server side script integration using PHP and newsletter coding.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

CTA. CENTRO DE TECNOLOGIAS AVANZADAS. ZARAGOZA

AngularJS Web Applications Development

11/2015 - 11/2015

Skills Acquired: AngularJS, SPA, Grunt.

iOS Application Design

03/2015 - 03/2015

Skills Acquired: iOS App creation frameworks and App design.

Mobile Applications Development with PhoneGap

12/2013 - 12/2013

Skills Acquired: PhoneGap, Apache Cordova, JavaScript, FrontEnd Development, NodeJS

> PHP and MySQL Web Applications Development

02/2010 - 04/2010

Skills Acquired: PHP, MySQL, Apache, Linux

SYSTEM ZARAGOZA. T&Z FORMACION.

Web Applications Design and Analysis

09/2002 - 12/2002

Skills Acquired: HTML, CSS, ASP and Access Database.

ZARAGOZA SCHOOL OF ART. Escuela de Arte de Zaragoza

› Graduation Final Project

09/2001 - 06/2002

Skills Acquired: 2D Animation, Illustration, Flash.

> CFGS Illustration and Graphic Design

09/1999 - 06/2001

Skills Acquired: Illustration, Design, Art